Register of the Joseph Freeman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1915-1964
  - Works Progress Administration. Federal Art Project
    - General. Newsletters, flyer, drawings and typescript writings (by Charmion von Wiegand?), clippings, letter, and statement by Paul Block, 1936-1940 (Folder 6)
    - Design Laboratory (program). Reports, press releases, biographical sketches, leaflets, and letter, 1936-1937 (Folder 7)
  - World politics. Memorandum, letters, pamphlets, clippings, press release, report, bulletins, statement by Benjamin Ginzburg, typescript book draft (incomplete) by R. D. Warth, and a typescript copy of Salvador Mendoza, "Monroe Doctrine and Fascist Holy Alliance,", 1915-1963 (Folder 8-11)
  - World War, Pamphlets, clippings, reports, newsletter, and miscellany, 1940-1964, 1939-1945 (Folder 12)
  - Young Communist League. Correspondence, pamphlet, and speeches, 1938-1943 (Folder 13)
- CARD FILE, circa 1940-1960
  Notes, name cross references, quotes, and miscellany relating to the career of Joseph Freeman.
  - Includes notes, name cross references, quotes, and miscellany (Boxes 187-189)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS, 1954-1962
  - Drawings by Joseph Freeman and others? (Box 190)
- SOUND RECORDINGS, undated (Record cabinet)
  - Four sound recordings of the song "Dogface Soldier,", undated
    Access
    Use copy reference number: 80159_a_0002984
    DOGFACE SOLDIER (Gold-Hart)/ 1. Fred Waring Orchestra/2. Echo Valley Boys/3. Mark Warnow-excerpt/4. 3rd Division Band. 1 disc.
  - Sound recording of Gene Derwood reading her poetry
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1920-1960
  914 prints, 31 postcards and 22 slides depicting Joseph Freeman and others, including Henri Barbusse, Earl Browder, Max Eastman, Sergei Eisenstein, Louis Fischer, Ivy Litvinov, Vsevold Meyerhold, Tina Modotti, Red Motley, Jose Clemente Orozco, Boris Pilnyak, Harry Truman, and Oscar Williams, and views of Mexico, Italy, Sudan, Hungary, and the Soviet Union.
  See photocard catalog for detailed description.
  - 49 prints depicting the Freeman family to, 1954 (Envelope A-B)
  - 57 prints and 12 duplicates depicting Joseph Freeman, 1920's (?) to 1951 (Envelope C-D)
  - 18 prints and 3 duplicates depicting Joseph Freeman with others, 1924-1957 (Envelope E)
  - 13 prints and 11 duplicates taken by Tina Modotti, including two inscribed by her, depicting Joseph Freeman and Ione Robinson, a cover for the New Masses, and a puppet maker, 1929 (Envelope F-G)
  - 36 prints depicting Ione Robinson in Mexico and elsewhere, including four inscribed to Freeman, 1927-1943 (Envelope H)
  - 23 prints and 1 duplicate depicting Freeman and others and scenes in Mexico, including two prints depicting Tina Modotti, (one photographed by Edward Weston); 1 print of Josi Clemente Orozco; and 1 inscribed print by Ione Robinson depicting a Diego Rivera mural, 1929 (Envelope I)
  - 7 prints depicting participants at the Congress of Mexican Artists and Writers, 1937 (Envelope J)
  - 19 prints and 1 duplicate depicting Joseph Freeman with others in New York, including the staff of the New Masses, (?); and unidentified people and places in New York, 1931 1930 (Envelope K)
  - 7 prints depicting Charmion von Wiegand, including one photographed by Lotte Jacobi, 2 prints depicting Freeman and Charmion, and 5 prints of scenes of Italy, undated; undated and 1962; 1952 (Envelope L)
  - 38 prints and 8 duplicates depicting Freeman, Charmion von Wiegand, and unidentified friends,; and their house in Accord, New York, undated and 1938 1934 (Envelope M)
  - 28 prints depicting bomb damage and scenes of daily life in France during World War II, including one print of Freeman in uniform in France, 1945 (Envelope N)
  - 15 prints depicting Freeman, Charmion von Wiegand, Ivy Litvinov, and others at a party in honor of Freeman's book, Never Call Retreat, 1943? (Envelope O)
  - 2 prints and 2 duplicates depicting banquets of the NCFA, including Freeman with others, Boston, Massachusetts, and Harry Truman with Red Motley, St. Louis, Missouri, 1955, 1953 (Envelope P)
  - 6 prints of murals from the Revere Room at the Hotel Lexington, New York City, depicting scenes of the American Revolution, including one scene with Freeman, 1937 (Envelope Q)
  - 10 prints and 6 duplicates depicting literary and political figures, including Henri Barbusse, Louis Fischer, Max Eastman, Oscar Williams, Earl Browder, and Karl von Wiegand, 1932-1942? (Envelope R)
  - 39 prints and 1 duplicate depicting Mr. and Mrs. Karl von Wiegand and scenes from their travels to Khartoum and Budapest, 1935-1936 (Envelope S)
  - 25 prints depicting Ivy Litvinov, (?); 5 prints depicting Maxim Litvinov, 8 prints depicting Ivy's family and friends, and 3 prints depicting places in Moscow, 1914-1943 undated; 1943-1960; 1931 (Envelope T-U)
  - 5 prints of Diego Rivera, 2 prints of Ivy Litvinov, and 2 prints of unidentified people, 1935; 1943; 1943 (Envelope mV)
  - 52 prints depicting Soviet artists and writers, including prints of Maksim Gorky and Boris Pilnyak, 1930's (Envelope W-X)
  - 20 prints and 1 duplicate depicting sets of productions by Vsevolod Meyerhold and of productions staged by others at the Meyerhold Theatre, and 1 inscribed print depicting Meyerhold, undated; 1927 (Envelope Y)
  - 20 prints depicting sets of film productions by Sergei Eisenstein, including three prints of Mexican people in costumes photographed by Eisenstein, and 1 of Eisenstein and others in Mexico, 1937; 1937 (Envelope Z)
  - 64 prints depicting sets of Russian film productions and performers, including twenty prints for Peter the Great, undated (Envelope AA-BB)
  - 5 prints depicting scenes from the film Storm Over Asia by V. Pudovkin, undated (Envelope mCC)
  - 6 prints depicting Soviet and other art, undated and 1927 (Envelope D)
  - 6 postcards and 2 duplicates depicting posters and people during the Spanish Civil War (Envelope EE)
  - 5 prints and 2 negatives of schools in Manzanillo designed by architect Carlos LeDuc, undated (Envelope FF)
  - 10 prints of political art depicting workers, 2 prints of demonstrations in Tampa? Florida, and 3 prints of workers and scenes in Duluth, Minnesota, 1930's; undated; 1931 (Envelope GG)
  - 6 prints depicting store displays of Davidson Bakeries, Chicago, and Gimble Brothers, Philadelphia, 1949 (Envelope HH)
  - 15 prints and 12 postcards depicting Russian ethnic musicians, buildings, and scenes in Russia; and 1 print of Lenin, undated (Envelope II)
  - 15 miscellaneous prints and 13 postcards depicting various people and places, including churches in Russia and the Moles Annual Award Dinner, 1949 (Envelope JJ)
  - 114 prints and 1 duplicate depicting unidentified friends, 1926-1953 (Envelope KK-NN)
  - One album containing 149 prints depicting Joseph Freeman, his family, and friends (Album fOO)
  - 22 Slides depicting various photographs and box 1 documents in the Freeman collection, undated (Slide Box 1)
  - Original photographs from envelopes F, G, and I - CLOSED (Box 191)